<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Eucalypto&#39;s Explorations</title>
    <link>https://blog.eucalypto.de/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Eucalypto&#39;s Explorations</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>mail@eucalypto.de (Viktor Papara)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mail@eucalypto.de (Viktor Papara)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.eucalypto.de/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>So, I&#39;ve started the 100 days of code challenge with PyBites</title>
      <link>https://blog.eucalypto.de/post/2019-11-20-100-days-of-code-pybites/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mail@eucalypto.de (Viktor Papara)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.eucalypto.de/post/2019-11-20-100-days-of-code-pybites/</guid>
      <description>So, I&amp;rsquo;ve started the 100 days of code challenge with PyBites. I really enjoy doing PyBites and this challenge is a nice push towards doing it regularly.
You can see my progress here: https://codechalleng.es/100days/eucalypto/4862
Right now I&amp;rsquo;m at day 27. Which is quite impressive for me but if you are reading this in the future, you can see if I managed to keep up until the 100 days!
This is also a good reason to use Twitter!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Jekyll! -- Again!</title>
      <link>https://blog.eucalypto.de/post/2019-09-27-welcome-to-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 19:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mail@eucalypto.de (Viktor Papara)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.eucalypto.de/post/2019-09-27-welcome-to-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Over the last several years I&amp;rsquo;ve not updated my blog because I starded using Dynalist. Its capable list creation and navigation made it feel natural to organize my thoughts and knowledge in a deep tree structure. This blog overlaps with this use-case because I started it to take notes for my future self.
Now I&amp;rsquo;m re-activating this blog to show the world what I&amp;rsquo;m up to. To give back at least some knowledge and insight that I gained by reading the wonderful blogs and tutorials of today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Command Line Goodies</title>
      <link>https://blog.eucalypto.de/post/2016-10-21-command_line/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mail@eucalypto.de (Viktor Papara)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.eucalypto.de/post/2016-10-21-command_line/</guid>
      <description>Watch Logfiles Watch a text file as it grows:
tail -f logfile.txt  Print out iso date format date --iso-8601=minutes  produces for example 2016-10-21T19:53+02:00</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Tips</title>
      <link>https://blog.eucalypto.de/post/2016-10-10-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 20:19:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mail@eucalypto.de (Viktor Papara)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.eucalypto.de/post/2016-10-10-ssh/</guid>
      <description>Run ssh-agent in remote login When you log into a machine with SSH and want to use a SSH key to do further stuff, like managing a remote git repository, you may have to
eval $(ssh-agent -s) ssh-add ~/.ssh/your_ssh_id according to this site. Then the shell remembers your SSH key as long as it is open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CentOS 7 Tips</title>
      <link>https://blog.eucalypto.de/post/2016-03-15-centos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 19:14:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mail@eucalypto.de (Viktor Papara)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.eucalypto.de/post/2016-03-15-centos/</guid>
      <description>Manage additional Repositories For CentOS 7 there exist additional repositories; for additional codecs for example. This website lists the most useful ones. I use the Nux-Dextop repository but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have it turned on the whole time.
So I use
sudo yum-config-manager --enable nux-dextop  to enable this repo. And when I&amp;rsquo;m done installing or updating with yum, I use
sudo yum-config-manager --disable nux-dextop  to disable this repo again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dropbox in CentOs 7</title>
      <link>https://blog.eucalypto.de/post/2016-03-15-dropbox-centos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 19:14:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mail@eucalypto.de (Viktor Papara)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.eucalypto.de/post/2016-03-15-dropbox-centos/</guid>
      <description>Install Dropbox in CentOS 7 This website has a nice overview over the installation process. First, you need to
sudo yum install libgnome and then download the Dropbox Fedora (.rpm) package from Dropbox and install it with
sudo rpm -ivh nautilus-dropbox[...].rpm Then you can start Dropbox and log in with your accound details.
Repair package manager yum If you use yum (e.g yum update) after Dropbox installation, you will probably encounter an error that a certain .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash Aliases</title>
      <link>https://blog.eucalypto.de/post/2016-03-11-bashrc-aliases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 18:44:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mail@eucalypto.de (Viktor Papara)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.eucalypto.de/post/2016-03-11-bashrc-aliases/</guid>
      <description>Aliases for command line in .bashrc In ubuntu the .bashrc file has a command that looks for ~/.bash_aliases and includes it. Here you find my .bash_aliases file with useful aliases.
This is the code in the .bashrc file:
# Alias definitions. # You may want to put all your additions into a separate file like # ~/.bash_aliases, instead of adding them here directly. # See /usr/share/doc/bash-doc/examples in the bash-doc package. if [ -f ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Tips</title>
      <link>https://blog.eucalypto.de/post/2015-04-27-git-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 02:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mail@eucalypto.de (Viktor Papara)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.eucalypto.de/post/2015-04-27-git-tips/</guid>
      <description>If you work with any kind of text files, a version control program is your best friend. And Git is probably the best.
The easiest way to learn git is tutorial. All other git commands you will learn by googling for them when in need.
If you want to share your code in an open source way, Github is nowadays the top choice. They also helped with the tutorial above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PDF-Tools</title>
      <link>https://blog.eucalypto.de/post/2013-04-14-pdf-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 19:14:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mail@eucalypto.de (Viktor Papara)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.eucalypto.de/post/2013-04-14-pdf-tools/</guid>
      <description>PDFs are a fine thing. But sometimes we want to edit them. Mostly for printing.
Pdfjam This command-line tool named pdfjam uses latex to edit PDFs. It should be available in the repositories of most Linux distros. There are also useful examples.
You can offset pages of a (twosided) document in order to make room for a binding, etc.:
pdfjam --twoside myfile.pdf --offset &#39;1cm 0cm&#39; --suffix &#39;offset&#39;  This doesn&amp;rsquo;t scale, it just shifts the content.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
